

KIM TOLMIE

18 Helissio Place, Castle Hill NSW 2154

(M): 0407 075 082

(E): kntolmie@bigpond.net.au

CAREER OVERVIEW

Originally a professional bookkeeper and office administration manager with over twenty years experience working within various industries, I took a career change in 2012 to pursue my passion for first aid, fire safety and community education and became a certified trainer and assessor. This career change has complimented almost ten years as a volunteer firefighter in the NSW Rural Fire Service. I have recently completed studying a Cert IV in WHS and achieved a distinction in graded assignments.

KEY STRENGTHS

- Strong leadership skills
- Strong and effective communication skills
- Highly organised and efficient
- High level of integrity
- Able to work autonomously or as part of a team environment
- Excellent people skills
- Proficient computer skills including Excel, Word, Outlook and PowerPoint

CAREER HISTORY

June 2012 – current

Accredited Trainer (casual)

Medilife

Medilife is an Australian owned company dedicated to providing professional Work Health & Safety services and products to business, industry and individuals. They provide specialist training in first aid, fire safety and WH&S both on-site and in public venues.

- Training & assessing the following nationally recognised courses:
 - Apply First Aid
 - CPR
 - Manage Asthma Emergencies
 - Manage Severe Allergic Reactions & Anaphylaxis
 - Develop Risk Minimisation & Management Strategies for Allergic Reaction & Anaphylaxis
 - Operate as part of an Emergency Control Organisation
 - Use Portable Fire Fighting Equipment

- Attend client sites in multiple locations to undertake training
- Provide flexibility in delivery of courses to suit the requirements of attendees
- Business development to expand both the business and courses offered
- Close liaison with office staff and managing director
- Presenter of the "Engaging the Student" session at the "Skills for Life"
 Conference hosted by Medilife

Dec 2012 – June 2013 Office Administrator (part time) GCA Electrical Australia Pty Ltd

GCA Electrical Australia is a small company providing electrical services, particularly within the petroleum industry, both locally and interstate.

Key Responsibilities

- Processing payroll
- Entry of creditors invoices
- Raising debtors invoices
- Maintenance of the Safety Management System & WHS issues
- ad hoc duties such as filing, photocopying, scanning, banking, collecting mail

April 2001 – June 2012 Professional Bookkeeper & MYOB Consultant Kim Tolmie (self employed)

Provision of bookkeeping, MYOB consultancy, and office administration services to various clients across an array of different industries. During this time I have also worked in conjunction with tax agents within public practice environments. Industries that I have been exposed to include (but not limited to) construction, printing, IT, finance, travel, manufacturing, health services, primary production, hospitality, retail and various service industries

- Accounts Payable
- Accounts Receivable
- Bank, credit card ,EFT and petty cash reconciliations
- Payroll including superannuation reporting and payroll tax reporting
- Accounting for GST including the preparation and lodgement of BAS and IAS returns
- General ledger maintenance including journal entries & reconciliation of accounts
- Maintenance of asset registers & depreciation schedules
- Accounting for Division 7A loans
- Accounting to trial balance, profit & loss and balance sheet, including the provision of management reports as required
- Providing cash flow projections
- Preparing budgets

- Completion of various obligations including (but not limited to) PAYG Payment Summaries, Workers Compensation Insurance Declarations & Superannuation reporting
- Tasks as required by each individual client such as reception/secretarial, banking, quote preparation, order placement, filing & photocopying, customer service
- Close liaison with external accountants
- Providing consultancy and support on-site including one-off system set ups and staff training
- PA and office administration

Sep 2001 – May 2002 Financial Assistant

The Mean Fiddler

A busy Irish pub located in Sydney's Rouse Hill. My duties also included double shifts over weekends and busy periods assisting with bar work and TAB and gaming functions.

Key Responsibilities

- Payroll for approximately 100 staff
- Data entry
- Balancing company safes
- Management and reconciliation of petty cash floats
- Emptying and counting poker machine hoppers
- Management reporting
- Accounts payable
- Relief bar and gaming duties
- Ad hoc duties as required

Sep 1999 – Mar 2001 Bookkeeper

Motorvation Prestige Paint & Panel

An automotive smash repair business involved in all aspects of motor vehicle repairs. This business was family-owned by my brother and purchased in August 1999. I assisted in getting the business operating.

- Production of monthly accounts to trial balance, profit & loss and balance sheet
- Maintenance of general ledger, debtors & creditors using Auto Quote software
- Bank reconciliations
- Payroll for 18 personnel, including superannuation reporting and group certificate preparation
- Banking
- Relief reception
- Maintenance of QA items (ISO 9002)
- Close liaison with external company accountant

Mar 1997 – Sep 1997 Executive Assistant Unitronix Pty Ltd

Suppliers of electronics and computer hardware primarily to military and defence clientele and telecommunications providers

Key Responsibilities

- Production of monthly accounts to trial balance, profit & loss, and balance sheet using MYOB
- Debtors & creditors
- Bank reconciliations
- Payroll for 5 personnel, including superannuation reporting
- Reception duties including extensive use of Microsoft Word and Excel
- Organisation of foreign currency payments
- Generating purchase orders and customer invoices
- Maintenance of QA items (ISO 9002)
- Assisting the managing director with the general running of the business

Jul 1994 – Nov 1995 Logistics Clerk

Serrol Ingredients

A division of Quality Bakers Australia Ltd at the time and now A B Mauri, Serrol is a leader in technical innovation and specialist ingredient and technology systems for the baked foods industry. Their products are a core ingredient in the likes of Buttercup products locally, as well as being exported around the world

- Processing local and export orders
- Production data entry
- Goods receipt data entry
- Co-ordinating production to meet export order requirements
- Liaison with freight forwarders, transport companies and couriers to ensure timely pick-up and delivery of orders
- Preparation of consignment notes and export order documentation in accordance with customs regulations
- Liaison with external agencies (such as AQIS and The Kashrut Authority), and consulates in order to effect export order requirements such as inspection, security sealing and Kosher certification
- Relief purchasing officer and receptionist
- Preparation and involvement in regular stock takes
- Organisation of foreign currency payments and telegraphic transfers
- Production reporting
- Management reporting

EDUCATION & TRAINING

2013 Medilife

CPR Refresher

2013 TAFE

Certificate IV in Work Health and Safety

2013 Skills for Life

Two day First aid professional development workshop

2012 Medilife

Apply First Aid (HLTFA301C)

Apply Advanced First Aid (HLTFA402C)

Manage First Aid in the Workplace (HLTFA403B)

Use Portable Fire Fighting Equipment (PRMPFES05B)

Operate as part of an Emergency Control Organisation (PUAWER005B)

Manage Asthma Emergencies (VU20011)

Provide first aid Management of severe Allergic reactions & Anaphylaxis (VU20296)

Develop risk minimisation & management strategies for allergic reaction &

Anaphylaxis (VU20297)

2012 Fire & Safety Australia

Enter confined Spaces (MSAPMPER205C)

Issue work Permits (MSAPMPER300C)

Work in Accordance with issued permit (MSAPMPER200C)

Conduct local risk control (RIIRIS201A)

Operate Breathing Apparatus (MSAPMOHS216A)

2010 Workplace Skills Australia

Certificate IV in Training & Assessment (TAE40110 & TAA40104)

2002 TAFE (Baulkham Hills Campus)

Responsible Service of Alcohol Responsible Conduct of Gambling

1995 SGS International Certification Services Pty Ltd

Internal Auditor Training QA ISO 9001/9002

1989 – 1991 TAFE (Baulkham Hills Campus)

Associate Diploma of Business (Accounting)

1983 – 1988 Gilroy College, Castle Hill

HSC (School prefect in year 12)

PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIPS

2005 – 2011 MYOB Professional Partnership Programme

2010 – 2012 Tax Practitioners Board

BAS Agent Registration

VOLUNTEERING – NSW RURAL FIRE SERVICE

I have been an active volunteer fire fighter with the NSW Rural Fire Service since 2003. Initially a member of the Glenhaven Brigade, I took a transfer to Glenorie Brigade in May of 2010. In January of 2013 I transferred to The Hills District Communications Brigade.

During my service within the RFS I have participated in both planned fuel management burns and emergency incidents (both locally and out of area), culminating in interstate service in Victoria and the provision of assistance in the clean- up of the Newcastle flood disaster in 2007.

Locally, my involvement has extended to being an active part of the brigade's Community Engagement team where activities such as property safety checks, primary and pre-school visits to assist with fire evacuation and lock-down drills and also fire safety education are undertaken. Active participation and organisation of community activities such as displays at the local school fair and the Growers Markets, where the provision of fire safety information is paramount, has also been undertaken.

At Glenorie Brigade, I took an integral role in the training and mentoring of brigade juniors in addition to being actively involved in the general operational functions of the brigade.

At a District level, I participated with a qualified team of instructors in a logistics and safety role on cross-cut chainsaw courses, and assisted with assessing on the Village Firefighter course and the Advanced Firefighter course.

REFEREES

Dean McDonald Learning and Development Consultant – Dean McDonald Consulting 0412 819 403

Matthew Lloyd Senior Deputy Captain – Glenorie Brigade – NSW Rural Fire Service 0409 664 211